48 chapter 49 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna suul chapter 49 My Last Home One day during this summer the
groom cleaned and dressed me with such extraordinary care that I thought some
new change must be at hand; he trimmed my fetlocks and legs, passed the tarbrush
over my Hooves and even parted my for loock I think the harness had an extra
polish. Willie seemed half anxious half merry as he got into the shase with his
grandfather. “If the ladies take to him,” said the old gentleman, “they'll be suited
and he'll be suited. We can but try.” At the distance of a mile or two
from the village we came to a pretty, low house, with a lawn and shrubbery at the
front and a drive up to the door. Willie rang the bell, and asked if Miss
Bloomfield or Miss Ellen was at home. Yes, they were. So, while Willie
stayed with me, Mr Thor good went into the house. In about 10 minutes he returned,
followed by three ladies; one tall, pale lady, wrapped in a white Shaw leaned on a
younger lady, with dark eyes and a merry face; the other, a very stately looking person, was Mrs
Bloomfield They all came and looked at me and asked questions. The younger lady—
—that was Miss Ellen— —took to me very much; she said she was sure she should like me,
I had such a good face.
The tall, pale lady said that she should always be nervous in riding behind a
horse that had once been down, as I might come down again, and if I did she should
never get over the fright. “You see, ladies,” said Mr Thor good
many First Rate horses have had their knees broken through the carelessness of
their drivers without any fault of their own, and from what I see of this horse I
should say that is his case; but of course I do not wish to influence you. If
you incline you can have him on trial, and then your coachman will see what he thinks of
him.” “You have always been such a good advisor to us about our horses,” said the
stately lady, “that your recommendation would go a long way with me, and if my
sister levinia sees no objection we will accept your offer of a trial, with
thanks.” It was then arranged that I should be sent for the next
day. In the morning a smart-looking young man came for me. At first he looked
pleased; but when he saw on my knees he said in a disappointed voice: “I didn't
think, sir, you would have recommended my ladies a blemished horse like
that.” “'Handsome is that handsome does',” said my master; “you are only taking him on
trial, and I'm sure you will do fairly by
him, young man. If he is not as safe as any horse you ever drove send him
back.” I was led to my new home, placed in a comfortable stable, fed, and left to
myself. The next day, when the groom was cleaning my face, he said: “That is just
like the star that 'Black Beauty' had; he is much the same height, too. I wonder
where he is now.” A little further on he came to the
place in my neck where I was bled and where a little knot was left in the skin.
He almost started, and began to look me over carefully, talking to
himself. “White star in the forehead, one white foot on the offside this little
knot just in that place the then looking at the middle of my back—“ —“and, as I am
alive, there is that little patch of white hair that John used to call
'Beauty's Threepenny bit'. It must be 'Black Beauty'! Why, Beauty! Beauty! do you know me?—
?—little Joe Green, that almost killed you?” And he began patting and patting me as
if he was quite overjoyed. I could not say that I
remembered him, for now he was a fine grown young fellow, with black whiskers
and a man's voice, but I was sure he knew
me, and that he was Joe Green, and I was
very glad. I put my nose up to him, and tried to say that we were friends. I
never saw a man so pleased. “Give you a fair trial! I should
think so indeed! I wonder who the rascal was that broke your knees, my old Beauty!
you must have been badly served out somewhere; well, well, it won't be my fault
if you haven't good times of it now. I wish John Manley was here to see you.”
In the afternoon I was put into a low park chair and brought to the door. Miss
Ellen was going to try me, and Green went with
her. I soon found that she was a good driver, and she seemed pleased with my
paces. I heard Joe telling her about me, and that he was sure I was Squire
Gordon's old “Black Beauty”. When we returned the other sisters came out to hear how I had
behaved myself. She told them what she had just heard, and said: “I shall
certainly write to Mrs. Gordon, and tell her that her favorite horse has come to
us. How pleased she will be!” After this I was driven every day for
a week or so, and as I appeared to be quite safe, Miss levinia at last ventured
out in the small close carriage. After this it was quite decided
to keep me and call me by my old name of “Black
Beauty”. I have now lived in this happy place a whole year. Joe is the best and
kindest of grooms.
My work is easy and pleasant, and I feel my strength and spirits all coming back
again. Mr thorg Good said the Joe the other day: “In your place he will last
till he is 20 years old— —perhaps more.” Willie always speaks to me when he
can, and treats me as his special friend.
My ladies have promised that I shall never be sold, and so I have nothing to
fear; and here my story ends. My troubles are all over, and I am at home; and often
before I am quite awake, I fancy I am still in the orchard at Berwick standing
with my old friends under the apple
trees END OF chapter 49 end of BLACK BEAUTY the autobiography
of a horse translated from the original